Guide to the American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students records
1948-1954
RU 466
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
(5 boxes)
The records consist of reports, personnel files, printed materials, correspondence, and student rosters documenting student affairs, travel, employment, and publicity documenting American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students program.
American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 3-D (YRG 3-D), Records documenting academic support functions at Yale University
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic
Biographical / Historical
American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students was established in 1948. The six-week program introduced individuals from other nations to the culture of the United States
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, personnel files, printed materials, correspondence, and student rosters documenting student affairs, travel, employment, and publicity documenting American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students program
Students, Foreign -- United States; American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students; Yale University -- Students
- Records, 1948-1954; Accession 1954-A-003
  - Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Council on Education (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Foundation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Friends (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American-Scandanavian Foundation (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American History (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anglo-American-Hellenic Bureau of Education (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report, First, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, Third, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual Report, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arts and Letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bagley, Mr. & Mrs. Henry W. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Balaban, Mr. Barney (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Banquet (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Barker Welfare Foundation (Hickox) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Blum, Mr. and Mrs. Robert (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bulletin, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Calendar and Organization, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Endowment (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carrie Chapman Catt (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Church of Christ in Yale (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Coffin, Mrs. W.S. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Columbia Foundation (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Commonwealth Fund (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cooperative League (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Deposits, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Driscoll, Mrs. Walter B. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Elks National Foundation (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Enders, Mr. Ostrom (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - English Language (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Evans, Mr. Thomas E. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Exchange of Persons (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Family Weekend, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Field, Mr. John, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Financial Accounts, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Foreign Student Orientation Program (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Foreign Student Orientation Program Policy (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - General, 1948-1951, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 42-46)
  - General Foods Corporation (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Gifts, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Hall, Mr. William E. (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Harbison, Mr. Hugh (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Heidelberg Students, Committee to Aid (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Hoaker, Mr. Richard (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Huntington, Mr. Robert W. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Index of International Agencies (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Institute of International Education, 1949-1953 (Box 2, Folder 55-59)
  - Institute of World Affairs (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - International Business Machines (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - International Research Fund (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - International Student Service (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Japanese Students, Department of the Army (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Josephs, Mr. Devereaux C. (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Knox, Seymour H. Foundation (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Kresge Foundation (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Lewis, Mr. Albert Baker (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Marshall, Mr. James A.K. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Medway Plan (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Meyer, Eugene (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Milbank, Albert G. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Motion Pictures (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - National Association of Foreign Student Advisors (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - National Student Association (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - New York Council for Foreign Students (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - New York Trip, 1948-1953 (Box 3, Folder 77-82)
  - Newspaper, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - O'Brien, Phillip (Judge) (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Old Dominion Foundation (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Organization 1955 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Petty Cash Reports, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 87-89)
  - Prospectus, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 90-92)
  - Prospectus, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Publicity, 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 94-100)
  - Publicity General (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Randolph, Mr. Francis F. (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Reader's Digest Foundation (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Recreation (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Reed, Mr. Joseph V. (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Relations with Federated Agencies (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Resor, Mr. Stanley (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Russell, Thomas W. (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Shell Oil Company (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Shelter Rock Foundation (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Social and Economic (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Socony Vacuum Oil Company (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - South and Central America (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Spyros P. Skouras (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - State Department (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - State Department Programs (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Statements of Accounts through, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Student Exchange--General (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Student Roster, 1948-1953 (Box 5, Folder 120-125)
  - Summer Sessions at Other Universities (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Tanglewood Trip, 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 127-130)
  - Term Paper (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Terms of Government Awards (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Texas Company (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Treasurer's Office Forms (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Treasurer's Office--Money Withdrawn, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Trips, general (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Weekend Hosts (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Weekend Trips, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 138-139)
  - Welch, Mr. & Mrs. Henry K. (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Whitney, John Hay Foundation (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - World Student Service Fund (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Yale Dorm Rules (Box 5, Folder 143)